Alex Cummaudo

Objective

With industry experience in the education, research and commercial sectors as a software engineer and teaching assistant, I am currently pursuing an undergraduate degree program in Computer Science and anticipate to graduate in 2016.

I help discover creative solutions to problems unsolved and envision seamlessness in products that enrich people's lives and connect us together. Having a thirst for knowledge and by keeping myself at the forefront of innovation, I aim to develop great ideas into great products.

Education

Bachelor of Science (Professional Software Development) Aug 2013-Present

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

High Distinction Average (GPA 4.0). Perfect marks of 100 in Introductory and and Object-Oriented Programming units; near-perfect marks of 98 in iOS Development and Usability.

Key Disciplines in Web and iOS Application Design/Development, Concurrent and Functional Programming, Data Structure Theory, Programming Languages Development, User Interface and Experience Design, Database Design and Programming

Bachelor of Information Technology Scholarship Program

Mar-lun 2013

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

High Distinction Average (GPA 4.0)

Key Disciplines in Information Systems, Management and Accounting. Completed one semester.

Victorian Certificate of Education (VCE)

Feb 2010-Nov 2012

Parade College, Bundoora

Australian Tertiary Admittance Ranking (ATAR) of 98.00 of 99.95.

Experience

Associate Developer

Aug 2015-Present

SEEK Ltd., Melbourne

- Development of search relevance ranking tools to improve search quality on SEEK's website.
- Focus on scalable cloud computing architecture with Amazon Web Services.
- Experience with continuous deployment and test-driven development environments.

Software Engineer

Aug 2014-Aug 2015

Swinburne NICTA Software Innovation Lab, Hawthorn

- Developed projects across various domains including fleet visualiser (via Google Maps) and management software, website development, and a web-based IDE front-end (http://rappt.io/).
- Web Application Development using AngularJS, Middleman, Node.js; iOS App Development in Objective-C.
- Experience in an Agile development environment; engaging in stand-ups and sprints.

Introduction to Programming Tutor

Mar 2014-Aug 2015

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

- Delivering learning content to tutorials of 25 students via interactive sessions mixed with liveprogramming, concept discussions, running group work activities and one-to-one feedback
- Assisting students understand fundamental programming concepts by assessing and providing feedback on weekly submitted work from students
- Preparing students for tests by running group exercises that allowed students to learn off each other; engaging student's learning by giving them the opportunity to work together
- Working with an enthusiastic team to gather teaching ideas and methods and contributing at weekly meetings, writing and sharing weekly reflections on classes

Web Application Developer (Pro Brono)

Winter Break-2014

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

- Building a large-scale web application utilised in tutoring position for student progress tracking (http://doubtfire.ict.swin.edu.au)
- Developing front-end development with Bootstrap and AngularJS
- Back-end development using Ruby on Rails, PostGres and Grape API

UI/UX Developer

Mar 2014-Aug 2014

LeadSoftware, Melbourne

- Lead UX and UI design for a large-scale on-board taxi system currently in deployment in a large taxi fleet
- Strong interaction with development team to explain prototypes and mock-ups developed and discuss feedback on implemented designs
- · Prototyping for apps on iOS and Android using a mix of whiteboard, Pixelmator and FluidUI techniques

Programming Help Desk Staff

Aug 2013-Dec 2013

Swinburne University of Technology, Hawthorn

- Assisting students learn syntax of C, Pascal, PHP, JavaScript
- · Explaining programming concepts to students and working through logic problems in a enthusiastic and approachable environment
- Help Desk initiative and staff commended by the Australian Computer Society

Skills **Core Strengths**

Web Application Development, Mobile Application Development, RESTful API Development, Concurrent Program Design, UI/UX Design and Prototyping, Website Administration, Teaching

Technical Skills

AngularJS, Node.js, iOS/Objective-C, JavaScript/CoffeeScript/DOM, SCSS/LESS/CSS3, Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, MEX C#/.NET, C/C++, Pascal

Software

Git, Apache2, Nginx, AWS, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Xcode, Xamarin, Coda 2, Trello, Pixelmator Lucidchart

Awards **Certificate of Achievement Awards**

November 2014, July 2015

Highest Achieving Student with the highest marks in nine subjects

Awarded by Prof. John Wilson - Executive Dean, Faculty of Science, Engineering and Technology, Swinburne University.

Certificate of Appreciation Award

1 Nov 2013

Swinburne ICT Student Ambassador Program

Awarded by Prof. Leon Sterling - Dean, Faculty of ICT, Swinburne University.

Vice Chancellor's Scholarship

31 Mar 2013

On outstanding academic excellence

Awarded by Prof. Linda Kristjanson - Vice Chancellor, Swinburne University.

Dux Award 8 Feb 2013

On achieving excellent VCE results and gaining one of the highest ATAR scores in the college. Awarded by Dr. Denis Moore - Principal, Parade College.

Extra Curricular

University

- Member of the Swinburne Tinkerers Guild
- Open Day Volunteering—discussing and advocating Swinburne degrees
- Spokesperson for Swinburne's Faculty of Information Technology
- Mentor for VCE students enrolled in Swinburne's Higher Education Studies within the VCE program

Hobbies and interests

- Hiking and jogging
- Antique computing
- Casual indie game developer at Paperbox Studios

Referrals

Dr. Andrew Cain Senior Lecturer, Swinburne University +61 03 9214 5324 acain@swin.edu.au

Dr. Rajesh Vasa Head of R&D, Swinburne Software Innovation Lab +61 435 016 006 rvasa@swin.edu.au

Mr. Allan Jones Team Lead, Swinburne Software Innovation Lab +61 03 9214 5707 ajones@swin.edu.au